Guide to the Amos Vogel Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Amos Vogel Papers,
1896-2001
[Bulk Dates: 1960-1990]
Vogel, Amos, 1921-
64.8 linear ft. (146 document boxes, 1 half-size box, 6 index card boxes, 1 flat box, 2 record box, 4 oversized folders)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY. 10027
MS#1432
5541450
This collection documents the professional work of film critic, professor, and author, Amos Vogel. The bulk of the records are concerned with numerous films that Vogel has screened for Cinema 16, the independent film society that he founded and directed for sixteen years, as well as administrative records, correspondence, photographs, and printed material
Biographical Note
Independent film in New York City has had several champions throughout its lifetime; one of the most vocal and committed being film critic and historian, Amos Vogel. Vogel, with his wife Marcia, has spent a lifetime promoting independent film and filmmakers, first through their non-profit membership organization, Cinema 16, and later as director of the New York Film Festival under the umbrella of Lincoln Center.
Amos Vogel (neé Vogelbaum) was born in Vienna Austria, on April 18, 1921. His mother, Matel, was a kindergarten teacher and his father, Samuel, a lawyer. According to an interview by Scott MacDonald, Vogel had always shown an interest in the cinema, frequenting many screenings and was a member of a large film society in Vienna. He was forced to emigrate during the Anschluss and fled to Cuba with his mother. After a short period in detention, Vogel was able to enter the United States settling in New York in 1939. He received a B.A. in Political Science and Economics at the New School for Social Research in 1949. During his time as an undergraduate, Vogel married Marcia Diener. It was also at this time that Vogel became aware of the abundance of 16 mm film that existed, but were not being shown to the public, mainly because of cost. These were not avant-garde film, but films that could be considered nonfiction, e.g. educational films, documentaries.
In 1947, Vogel and his wife, Marcia, founded Cinema 16 which grew into the largest film society within the United States. At its pinnacle, the society had seven thousand members who regularly attended screenings at the High School of Fashion Industries (in Manhattan) and other locations throughout New York City. Vogel, his wife Marcia, and later his assistant Jack Goelman spent countless hours screening films, creating events based upon numerous themes, and writing extensive program notes in order to engage their audiences with independent cinema. By the 1950s, Cinema 16 had begun to establish itself as a salient distributor of independent film. These were distributed to film societies, universities, museums, and other interested parties.
As the influence of Cinema 16 spread, Vogel added special events to the regular and scrupulously planned screenings. A Children's Cinema designed for aged 4 through 8 ran for two seasons. For three years, in collaboration with the Curator of Film at the George Eastman House, Vogel brought Cinema 16 members onto "field trips" where they spent an entire weekend devoted to nothing but film. There were courses sponsored by Cinema 16 at local universities and institutions. Several publications were issued, including an essay on Kurasawa's Rashomon by Parker Tyler and a quarterly entitled Filmwise. Awards, such as the Robert Flaherty Award for documentary film and the Creative Film Foundation Awards (1956-1960), for experimental films, helped focus attention upon the growing interest in independent and experimental cinema.
By the early 1960s, running Cinema 16 became increasingly difficult. Rising financial costs, coupled with competition from other entertainment venues, such as art-house theaters and television made sustaining a viable and vibrant organization almost impossible. Cinema 16's final season was in 1963. In the early 1990s, Cinema 16 retrospectives and tributes were conducted at the Anthology Film Archives, the Museum of Modern Art, and the Film Forum.
Vogel went on to be director of The New York Film Festival, a position he held from 1963 until 1968 and director of the Film Department (1964-1968), both at Lincoln Center. Later he served as a film consultant for Grove Press and National Educational Television, and in 1973, was named a professor of communications at the Annenberg School of Communications, University of Pennsylvania. He held this position until 1993. Vogel has also been visiting faculty at Harvard, New York University, and Columbia University.
In addition to his teaching, Amos Vogel is a prolific author. He was a columnist for \The Village Voice and Film Comment from 1971 until 1985. In 1974, he wrote a book entitled Film as a Subversive Art, an analysis of the ways in which "subversive" material, be it ideological or sexual, can be used within the medium of film in order to manipulate the viewers conscious and unconscious mind. Vogel examines over five hundred films, many of which were rarely seen or banned works. The book was translated into five languages and issued in ten editions. Vogel was also a frequent contributor to The New York Times, Cineaste, Saturday Review, Quarterly Review of Film Studies, Hollywood Quarterly, Afterimage, Antioch Review, and other film publications.
He was a member of innumerable international film juries and was an invited guest of Cannes, Moscow, Berlin, Venice, Karlovyvary, Oberhausen, and many other international film festivals. Honors for Amos Vogel include the 1994 and 1998 Award for Pioneering Work and Writings on behalf of Independent Cinema from the Anthology Film Archives and the Robert J. Flaherty International Film Seminars, respectively. He also holds an honorary M.A. from the University of Pennsylvania.
Marcia Vogel passed away in February 2009. She is survived by her husband and her two sons, Steven and Loring. Amos continues to live in New York City.
Scope and Content
This collection documents primarily the professional work of Amos Vogel. The bulk of the records are concerned with films that Vogel screened for festivals, courses, and Cinema 16. These records consist of film files, notebooks, and hundreds of stills from films that were rarely seen. The second largest portion of the collection is writings, in the form of articles, essays, speeches, short stories, manuscripts, and numerous drafts. Also included are administrative records pertaining to the management of Cinema 16, audio visual material, such as teaching slides, and a small amount of personal documents from Vogel's early life.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in six series.
Series I: Cinema 16, 1914-1996
Subseries I.1: Administrative Records, 1914-1994
Subseries I.2: Correspondence, 1947-1996
Subseries I.3: Program Notes, 1947-1963
Series II: Film, 1896-2001
Subseries II.1: Film Files, 1896-1993
Subseries II.2: Director Files, 1930-1985
Subseries II.3: Notebooks, 1974-1997
Subseries II.4: Festivals and Conferences, 1934-1997
Subseries II.5: Subject Files, 1947-2001
Series III: Writings, 1896-1996
Subseries III.1: Manuscripts, 1896-1979
Subseries III.2: Lectures and Speeches, 1957-1994
Subseries III.3: Academic Courses, 1951-1995
Subseries III.4: Short Stories, 1960-1985
Subseries III.5: Other Writings, 1958-1996
Series IV: Photographs, 1920-1999
Subseries IV.1: General, 1927-1999
Subseries IV.2: Film Stills, 1920-1994
Subseries IV.3: Slides, 1970s-1988
Series V: Audio Visual Material, 1946-1980s
Series VI: Personal, 1932-2000
Subseries VI.1: About Amos Vogel, 1960s-2000
Subseries VI.2: Early Life, 1932-1937
Subjects
Annenberg School of Communications (University of Pennsylvania); Cinema 16 (Society: New York, N.Y.); Cinema 16 (Society: New York, N.Y.)--History--20th century.; Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts.; New York University.; American Film Festival--(New York, N.Y.); Cannes Film Festival.; Internationale Filmfestspiele Berlin.; Deren, Maya.; MacDonald, Scott, 1942-; Vogel, Amos.; United States--Social conditions.; Children's films.; Documentary films.; Experimental films.; Film festivals.; Independent filmmakers.; Independent films.; Independent films--History.; Motion pictures.; Articles; Essays.; Film clips.; Film stills.; Journals (accounts).; Short stories.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
Glenn Horowitz. Purchase, 2005
- Series I: Cinema 16, 1914-1996
  Series I consists of records documenting the creation and day-to day-maintenance of the independent film organization Cinema 16 from its inception until its dissolution in 1963. The records provide insight into the daily work needed to promote the society, procure the various films, and operate in a successful and sustainable manner. The series is arranged in three subseries: Administrative Records, Correspondence, and Program Notes. Please note that the records are not limited to the lifetime of the organization; however, but also document the effect that Cinema 16 had on later groups and film societies.
  - Subseries I.1: Administrative Files, 1914-1994
    Subseries 1 contains general administrative records about the workings of the society. Special events, such as the Children's Cinema, a series dedicated to providing unusual and unique films to children, and the "field trips" to the George Eastman House in Rochester, New York are documented here. This subseries also holds administrative records concerning other related film projects conducted by Amos and Marcia Vogel during the lifespan of the society as well as articles and interviews with the founders.
    - General, 1947-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - The Archive Film Society, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Articles by Amos Vogel, 1948-1963, 1984-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Articles by Others, 1948-1963, 1976-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Charles Theatre, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Children’s Cinema
      - Banner (Box 15-K-5)
      - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Film Catalogues and Listings, undated, 1949-1959, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 7 to 8)
      - Finances, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Printed Material, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Program Notes, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Publicity and Mailing Lists, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Cinema 16 Retrospective, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - The Creative Film Awards, 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Deren, Maya, 1946, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Display Book Material, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Distribution Lists, undated, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Education
      - An Anti-Catalog, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - "Before the Revolution," 1980s (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - The Cinema 16 Film Center at The New School, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - "Film: Landmarks of a Visual Art"--Pratt Institute, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - "The Independent Film" Lecture Series, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - “New Frontiers in the Cinema”--New York University, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Experimental Film Catalogue
      - General, undated, 1954-1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Contracts, 1954-1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Finances, 1950-1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Printed Material, undated, 1950-1963 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Publicity, 1950-1957 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Feature Film Society, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Film-Makers Cooperative, undated, 1961-1963 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Free Cinema from Great Britain," 1956 or 1957 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Fund for Adult Education, undated, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - The Future of Film as Art Conference, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - George Eastman House Trip, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - George Eastman House Trip, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Griffith, Richard, 1959-1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - MacDonald, Scott, 1982-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Master List of Films, undated, 1914-1963 (Box Index 1)
    - Museum of Modern Art
      - General, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Budgets, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Programming, 1961 or 1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Other Film Societies, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Pickpocket, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material
      - General, undated, 1940-1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - "Art in Cinema," 1946 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Brochures, 1951-1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Filmwise 2: Maya Deren, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - "The Mystery of Rashomon," 1952 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Press Releases, 1947-1970, 1986-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Programming, 1949-1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Publicity, 1947-1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Summary--Cinema 16, 1947-1963, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Summary--New York Film Festival, 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Supplementary Series, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Technical Notes, 1950s (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Tourtelot, Madeline, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Subseries I.2: Correspondence, 1947-1996
    Letters found in this subseries are between Amos Vogel and various film distributors, Cinema 16 members, potential guest speakers, such as Alfred Hitchcock and Fritz Lang, film makers, and fans. There are also documents held in this subseries that are about specific individuals, rather than correspondence with. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by either the last name of the individual and institution or by the topic, for example "Art in Cinema."
    - General, undated, 1948-1981, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Anderson, Lindsay, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Anger, Kenneth, 1947-1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Arnheim, Rudolf, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Art in Cinema," 1947-1955 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Bachmann, Gideon, 1955-1959 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Belson, Jordan, 1949-1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Belson-Conger, Jane, 1960-1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Berenger, Jean, 1950-1957 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Biographic Cartoon Films Ltd., 1957 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Brakhage, Stan, 1956-1966 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - British Transport Films, 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Broughton, James, 1947-1950 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Buñuel, Luis, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Burkhardt, Rudolph, 1948-1955 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Cage, John, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Card, James, 1953-1958 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Cassavetes, John, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Cavalcanti, Alberto, 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Cinema, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Cinema 16, Inc., 1953-1960 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Cinémathèque Française, 1948-1953 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Clarke, Shirley, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Cocteau, Jean, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Contemporary Films, Ltd., 1958-1962 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Cornell, James, 1948-1957 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Cornell Study Center, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Creative Film Foundation, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Crockwell, Douglass, 1948-1950, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Crosby, Caresse, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Dreyer, Carl Theodore, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Ehrhardt, Alfred, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Filmaufbau, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Film Culture, 1955-1960 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Film Forum, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Film Polski, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Flaherty, Robert and Frances, 1947-1957 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Forces et Voix de France, 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Form Letters, undated, 1959-1961 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Frank, Robert, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Haanstra, Bert, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Haamid, Alexander, 1948-1954 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Hitchcock, Alfred, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Kees, Weldon/Kees, John, 1956-1958 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Kluge, Alexander, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Kramer, Stanley, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Kuhn, Rodolfo, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Lang, Fritz, 1956-1958 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Lee, Francis, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Library and Museum of the Performing Arts, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - The Living Theatre, Inc., 1955 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - London Film Society, 1950s (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lorentz, Pare, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Maas, Willard, 1949-1957 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Macgowan, Kenneth, 1949-1956 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Markopoulos, Gregory, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Markopoulos, Gregory, 1950-1966 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Marx, Groucho, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Mazetti, Lorenza, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - McLaren, Norman, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Mock, Flora, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Museum of Modern Art, 1950-1956, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Peterson, Sidney, 1947-1953 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Putteman, Peter, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Reisz, Karel, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Renoir, Jean, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Resnais, Alain, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Richter, Hans, 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Rohauer, Raymond, 1953-1963 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Roos, Jorgen, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Rose, Tony, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Schapiro, Meyer, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Stark, Leonard, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Storck, Henri, 1950-1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Tourtelot, Madeline, 1955-1960 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Tregillus, Leonard, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Turner, Leslie, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Tyler, Parker, 1948-1957 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Varda, Agnes, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Vesely, Herbert, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Vickrey, Robert, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Vidor, King, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Vishniac, Roman, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Vorkavich, Slavko, 1949-1956 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Weiss, Peter, 1956-1964 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Whitney, John, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Wright, Basil, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Wynn Jones, Stuart, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Young, Christopher, 1950-1957 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Zinnemann, Fred, 1954-1957 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Subseries I.3: Program Notes, 1947-1963
    Subseries 3 is composed of programs handed out at each Cinema 16 screening. The pamphlets span the entire existence of Cinema 16 and present a detailed overview of the types of films Vogel chose. These programs provided basic information concerning each film such as the titles, dates of creation (and release if of interest), and biographies of the directors and actors. More importantly, the film is placed within an historical context and oftentimes briefly analyzed for the audience. Information about future screenings and upcoming special events were also listed in the program notes.
    - 1947 October-December (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - 1948 February-December (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - 1949 February-December (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - 1950 January-December (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - 1951 January-December (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - 1952 January-December (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - 1953 January-April (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - 1953 October-1954 May (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - 1954 October-1955 May (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - 1955 October-1956 May (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - 1956 October-1957 May (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1957 October-1958 May (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1958 October-1959 May (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1959 October-1960 May (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1960 October-1961 May (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1961 October-1962 May (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1962 October-1963 May (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Series II: Films, 1896-2001
  Series II comprises the bulk of the Amos Vogel Papers. Vogel screened hundreds of films for showing at Cinema 16 as well as for the various film festivals he organized and ran, and the guest lectures and regular classes that he taught. Many of these films exist only in this collection and are either out-of-print or inaccessible. In addition to the film files themselves, Vogel kept files on specific directors and notebooks from conferences and panels. Other film-related records held within this series include documents relating to Lincoln Center and the establishment of the New York Film Festival.
  - Subseries II.1: Film Files, 1896-1993
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by the title of the film or film series. Titles listed vary widely from obscure films that may have only been shown for Cinema 16 events to Hollywood-produced blockbusters. The files consists of promotional material such as fliers, posters, quotes, plot summaries, and biographical information about the film’s creators, articles and reviews from major news and film sources, analyses by other film critics, and photographs. Please note that all film stills have been separated and may be found in Series V, Subseries 2. Most importantly, Vogel himself often wrote notes about the films in preparation for published articles, which were included in this subseries, programs notes for Cinema 16, and lecture material for his courses. Within this subseries is a substantial number of oversized printed material in the form of posters, publicity-focused advertisements, and pamphlets.
    - A, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - A La Folie, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Abel Gance: Yesterday and Today, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - About Something Else, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Abraham and Isaac, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Accattone, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Ace in the Hole, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - The Accused, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Actua-tilt, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - An Actor and His Director Look at Footage Showing Preparation for an Unmade Film, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Acupunctural Anaesthesia, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Adalen 31, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Adebar, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Adolescence, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Adventures of Asterisk, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Adventures of Jimmie, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - L'Age d'Or, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Age of Infidelity, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Ages of Christ, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Agnus Dei (Lamb of God), 1971 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Aguirre, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - AI, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Airborne, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Akbar, undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Akran, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - A La Mode, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Alexander the Great, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Ali, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Alice in the Cities, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Alice's Restaurant, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Il Alienista, 1967, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Alliance for Progress, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - All Nudity Shall Be Punished, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - All Messed Up (Manji), 1964 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Alle Juden Raus!, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Allures, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Alone, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Alphaville, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - A Married Couple, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Un Ameleto di Mene, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - America: Everything You've Ever Dreamed Of, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - America Is in Real Trouble, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - American Friend, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - American Pie, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - American Revolution 2, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - The American Soldier, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - America's Pop Creator: Robert C. Skull-Contemporary Art at Auction, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Among Men, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - L'Amour Fou, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Anais Observed, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Analogies, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - And God Created Woman, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 22)